[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
hey folks welcome to the junkyard love
podcast it's me
your host mayor from the powerpuff girl
tv show series this week we've got jc
randall on the podcast
i'm pumped to share wow we really
covered some great stuff
childhood trauma healing spirituality
spiritual awakenings
um oh man just so much good stuff this
episode is packed full
of fantastic bites bits snippets
gold nuggets if you do enjoy anything
from this podcast if you found something
that was profound if
either of us says something that really
stands out to you if there's something
that's said that is helpful to you in
your life or
to someone that love that you love in
your life just maybe
take a little screen grab send it to
them tell him to check it out and send
the time to start it at um i think this
uh this stuff really helps actually heal
people when
it gets shared and when it gets to to
the right ears
so i wish that for you all uh i hope you
are all doing well
uh and then this particular time of of
covid
in in this pandemic and now it's been
almost a year and
um you know as a as a mental health
advocate i you know i just have to say i
see you all of you
everybody i see you like this is hard
right now
what's going on everybody's life
trajectory has been changed
we've now been forced to take different
forks in the in
the path of our lives so um
if you're going through it right now
just just know like i see you
i see you you're gonna be okay you've
got this you can handle this
just keep consuming content like this
just keep trying
trying to consume positive good content
be nice to yourself
please please please be drinking your
water stretch
movement this is the time when we got to
be taking the extra time out of our day
we've got to be taking the extra time to
to love ourselves
i mean it's just as simple as that
you've got to be loving yourself
extra right now you got to be patient
with yourself you've got to be
willing to not be so hard on yourself
right now
stuff is crazy and it's happening to
everybody across the world our country
is pretty nuts right now but
across the world man humans are
experiencing a new
virus and the leaders have not responded
well to it
the society we live in
is undergoing vast change
um and we're all going to be part of it
but
that change is is uh uncomfortable for
now so
just know i i see you it's gonna be all
right
we're gonna get through this
everything's good everything's gonna be
okay
we got this keep learning keep feeding
that soul knowledge
and let's get rocking and rolling with
this podcast
miss jc have a good one
all right well ladies and gentlemen
welcome to
the junkyard love podcast i am here with
my friend jacy hello jc
hi how's it going it is going good my
friend it's good to see you it's good to
have you on the podcast again
um you were one of the first you were in
the first ten
i ended up deleting my i probably told
you the story might when i very first
started the podcast
i deleted my first five episodes like
completely on accident i
i messed up but you were in the first 10
for sure
oh no yeah um
me too stumble through i was still
trying to
figure out a direction for the podcast
at the beginning you know i wanted to
just have it
conversational and casual but i also
really wanted to do
something mental health somehow helping
people somehow
giving people valuable content and like
allowing people to
maybe see new ways and new perspectives
um in their own life and relate to the
other person so
you definitely i really appreciate you
coming on in the first stages and
letting me just
totally stumble through not knowing
exactly what i'm doing i still don't
really know what i'm doing i definitely
still stumbled through 100
but at the beginning listening back it's
almost cringy
in some aspects um
yeah i'm sorry no 100 i agree with you
sorry i didn't
cut you off but um but yeah no i think
that same thing when you shared that
like
i like listen back to that too and think
of like where i'm at today and i'm like
oh
i'm like cringing uh some of the things
in the conversations
i posted on my story to share them like
i think of so much growth
from compared to that first episode to
this one
well so um let's give let's give a
background like so
let's see how have you changed since
then i mean you've been doing a ton of
work you've started your own business
i mean things have totally shifted
there's a lot of changes
um in the in the world for everybody
listening to the podcast
but also just in in yourself in your
self-development
um so what is your what has your changes
looked like
in the last year or since that last
podcast like what are you
what are you up to now jc oh
that's a good question um so many
changes what am i up to so yeah
starting my website my business um i've
kind of stepped
more into like my spirituality um
into like my channeling my gifts
whatever you want to call it um and i've
been able to
like help people also helping myself you
know because like you
help and work with people and it's
almost like a reflection mirror
and almost simultaneously like whatever
they're releasing i end up releasing
within that space as well
um and yeah being like
more present being more
less anxious actually less because i
like hopping on that podcast i was like
so reserved and so quiet and like hadn't
really found like my
space in like the social media world or
just like
my personal world in general and like
being able to really expand um
building relationships and like healthy
long-standing relationships that are
near and dear which like i've always
kind of struggled with it's kind of like
one of my um
like attachment issues is you know
building
long-standing relationships and those
kind of dynamics and
yeah growing into um being like a family
um person which i never really was i was
always super disconnected from family
and kind of
you know learning how to really love my
family for who they are and what they
are in this moment and not kind of
expecting anything from them and
being present more and showing up for
the people who need it and yeah that's
kind of what's been
happening yeah okay well well how'd you
get there like what have you
what have you been doing what was your
um trajectory
i suppose since last time like so you've
been doing let's let's explain
you know you've been healing um you know
what i don't know if you use
terminologies like shadow work
um you know going through childhood
traumas like all that
this sort of stuff so what what is what
is healing like how can you say if i say
how have you changed
in in the last year and you were
explaining to someone like here's how
you can change and here's these things
that i discovered like
trauma healing and working with
working with your past and reframing
your your limiting beliefs these sorts
of things so
how did you get to where you're
different than you are now
or or were back then really oh how
it changed how i got here doing all the
work um
so i hit a like low point um
i mean like i i don't know like i
went through you know super serious like
traumatic event i don't really
like i haven't really communicated with
the world about that
um in general but um
yeah going through like a super serious
traumatic event like losing
you know uh near and dear person to me
and kind of going through that
shift um and just like watching that
play out like watching this person like
lose their life and like being you know
in the front seat of that
and um i numbed myself out for a long
time
and kind of used like my codependency to
numb that out and um
yeah i transitioned into like a really
low energy supers depressed like
like not suicidal but like i just like
didn't want to be here i didn't want to
be alive i didn't want to
do anything i couldn't get out of bed to
go to work i couldn't like
i couldn't do a lot of things and um
i just hit a really really really low
point and i was like
man i cannot do this like i'm not going
to make it like another year
if i like sit in this position and
so i had to really dig deep and it
started from
um yeah just not wanting to be sad i
think i went to therapy i started going
to therapy
after like a year after like
my accident and um
the therapist looked at me and she
literally said you have to do the work
like it's hard work to be happy
and i just was like so taken back like
my victim
mentality was like what it doesn't just
happen to me
like the world just doesn't give me that
like yeah
um and so from there i was like you know
what
you're right like i dug deep
i started doing the work like yeah a lot
of
journaling a lot of therapy a lot of
working out i had to start you know
getting my heart rate up and
doing that and a lot of i've had a lot
of help from people
um too like you know
family members i have a
family member who's like super spiritual
she's actually a medium this is kind of
where like all my
gifts come from um and i work with her
pretty frequently and pretty often and
she was kind of like my backbone for a
minute
um and yeah i got into
this relationship now that i'm in and
engaged
to get married to um who is
so like independent and strong and like
you know had to really put his [__]
together um and so
me coming into that dynamic very
codependent very broken very victim hug
very
not on my two feet like not standing on
my own and he was just like
you hot like i'm here for you but like
you have to do it and
um so that also helped me too so yeah um
and then it's just kind of like a spiral
effect from there really
yeah looking at myself getting up in the
mirror and just being like okay this is
what i want to do
and yeah i don't even know it's just
been
how i dug so deep into this like
awesome aspect and like who i am today
but it just kind of
all fell into place and now i love doing
the work i love getting up
and i love you know doing the little
things and filling up my day with
stuff that you know may seem not
super fun but um after you do it it
gives you that like
fulfillment of like me and i
accomplished that and now i feel so much
better
mentally and yeah i don't know
yeah no no it definitely does um it
makes me think of
uh you've probably heard this analogy
before because i was thinking of like oh
yeah you know you're
you've rebuilt yourself you know you've
built yourself into who you are and
you've
you know but i was also thinking you've
gotten rid of who you aren't
and i was thinking of this analogy that
you may have heard this
basically like a block of clay the
sculpture exists within the block of
clay you just have to remove
the parts that are not the sculpture you
know it's it's in there
and so um it sounds like you're kind of
you know building into things that were
always there
or um leaning into parts of yourself
that were kind of
under underneath some clay so to say
um and you said something that stuck out
to me is is
you know you're when you're talking to
your therapist and yeah
your victim mindset peeks up and starts
like trying to defend you and so you
know that's kind of like being triggered
so
let's explain um like what's the
difference between a victim mindset and
say a growth mindset
for someone who because for me when i
think of me being a victim
it's not it's not until i look back at
me in retrospect and be like oh i was
putting myself on the victim sabbat but
during those points i wouldn't have said
oh i'm i'm acting like the victim right
now i'm being dramatic jake
i would have just found justification so
what is the victim mindset
and what is growth mindset or where
you're at now
yeah so the victim mentality is like
the world owes me something everything's
happening to me
not for me um you know everything that's
happened
is just so hard and so like
disheartening and it's almost like you
know you feel like the world's just kind
of caving in on you
and you're incapable of stopping it
which is
now trying to transition into like a
growth mindset where like
the world can feel like it's caving in
but instead of sitting
and letting it you kind of like push it
back up and you're like i've got this
the world's happening
for me not to me um and
you're capable of making all of the
transitions and the shifts
in your mentality how you speak how you
present yourself how you show up
um for your people surrounding you
whatever the case may be
um and it really and i'm not gonna say
positive and like an unhealthy positive
manner but just like
being real and bring being honest with
yourself and the fact that like
um you're capable of making those
changes and you're capable of
doing the work um the victim mentality
is like
i don't want to do the work i just want
it to be done and the growth mindset is
like i'm ready to do the work like let's
[__] go
so did you have to start like what was
the internal talk for you
did you because for me i asked because i
basically had started i had you know my
sudden realizations of sorts
but then it was like wow i've got a lot
of work to do and for me i just started
really inserting tons of um
like audible and youtube content and
like reading more books and stuff
kind of shoving the tony robbins
positive
mindset just just to kind of like
counterbalance when i would have those
thoughts now i have awareness of it and
so my
my brain is telling me like oh this is
oh another bad thing happened just my
luck
of course this is what happens to jake
this is the you know re
like just reifying my or reaffirming my
self-loathing story with with that
victimhood but i started
changing my daily inner talk by
listening to
you know tony robbins and a lot of
jordan peterson
and you know just motivational stuff how
did you
adjust your inner talk your inner voice
what happened for you there at the
beginning
um it was actually eckhart tolle oddly
that
we talked about his book yeah we went on
a walk yeah we did
so it was uh there's a couple books but
that was like really the transitional
moment so actually before the accident
so this was like cinco de mayo 2017.
um before that i had moved up to
orcas island i was living there with my
best friend and i had
uh i lived in an rv with like no running
water
just power and i lived by myself with my
cat and i was just like
chilling like i was just like i'm here
to heal i'm here to do this and i was
working a little part-time gig
um at this little shop and
i would only work a couple hours a day
um and i decided to go to like a little
bookstore because there's like a little
town little bookstore um
and i had no idea who eckhart tolle was
and i picked up
the power of now and
i was like oh yeah i'm gonna read this
book like that was kind of the starting
point of like my
okay i'm gonna start healing um and i
showed it to my friend and she's like
super
spiritual intuitive like we yeah she's
just awesome too
um and she's like oh i love him i listen
to his audiobooks all the time when i'm
like driving home because it's like a
you know an hour ferry ride and then a
three and a half hour drive
to town long view yeah so
um i was like okay cool so i started
reading that book
um and it just really taught me how to
be present and like not which is
you know a super big factor in healing
and being happy and being just like
i don't know feeling whole and feeling
complete is being right here right now
like nothing else matters like the past
isn't real the future is not real
all you have is right now and i remember
i was hanging out with a friend and i
remember reading this part
in this book and it said um
sit where you're at go sit outside and
like just
look at the trees and pay attention to
like what aura gives off like what the
leaves look like what the
you know the whole tree in itself like
that is like
an energy that's like a being like look
at what it's
presenting to you um and i still like
four years later still look at and hold
on to that just phrase in that entire
book
and um that was kind of what
shifted my process into like looking at
my past
and being like oh my gosh poor me to
like it doesn't [__] matter
like none of it matters all i have is
right here right now and
i create that moment so yeah
that that book was a really monumental
one i literally recommend that book to
anybody and everybody all the time
because
it just it was a huge shift for me and
then the
there's another one you can heal your
life by
louise hay or louise k i can't remember
her last name
um yeah that one was just a
i don't know why but those two are the
only two books that really
stick to me yeah i haven't i actually
haven't read either of those i haven't
read the power of now
still um i consume a good amount of
eckhart like i go
every couple months i'll go through you
know like a week or a week or two
of listening to a lot of his his
lectures and talks but i still haven't
read the power of now
but i've heard from more than just you
that it's it's like a life-changing book
definitely a perspective shifter
yeah honestly i don't know if i would
have been able to make the transition or
have
the perspective going because i read
that as starting like february
four years ago and then like after
my accident like that was like still
sticking with me in such a huge
monumental
um like book
in my life and it really helped me
through a lot of
you know i like that was just a huge
transitional period in my life and
i really needed that so i'm really
thankful that i got to read that
beforehand
um yeah yeah wow okay so
going back to your your flip from victim
mentality
into growth mindset so like what would
your if you had to compare
okay here's what jc did six months ago
when she didn't realize that she was
being a victim
and then here's what jc does now when
she has these same thoughts she's these
same
because you know there's still there's
still days like you're on your path of
healing but i'm sure there's still days
correct me if i'm wrong where
you feel down where you feel where your
internal dialogue
is the victim mindset you have to catch
yourself uh what what is the difference
between
then and now like what do you tell
yourself now or six months after
realizing you had been the victim
difference between linda now is like
back then
i was like
shovel in hand digging you know what i
mean like oh my gosh
um
let me find the words to elaborate this
in like the right way that i want to
like each time i was digging i was like
well this person said this to me
and like i don't deserve that i don't
understand why like i'm not doing
anything
wrong um or like you know
my parents did this to me and like i
don't understand like why do you
you know do this or whatever the case
may be
um and then also just now
stepping out of that is not having any
expectations of people or having um
that's the words i'm looking for i'm so
sorry
i guess now stepping out of that would
be
just being i don't know grateful um
for everything that i've like gone
through and understanding that
it's all for like a deeper purpose and a
deeper meaning and
knowing that i like ultimately
spiritually chose to go through those
and so i hold on to that
um and yeah that's kind of what i hold
in
i can elaborate that too i guess like
spiritually when you
i don't know we're going to go real
spiritual here so like when you go all
in jc definitely
okay so when you like incarnate right
you come here you your energy your soul
becomes like a human being like
you ultimately like choose the life
path that you can have you can make
different decisions and it can alter
your pathway
ultimately you have like this you know
certain direction certain pathway
that you can follow making each decision
so
the parents that you have you choose the
life that you grow up
as a child you choose um so all the
trials
all the trauma all of everything that
feels like an uphill battle and an
uphill climb
you choose coming here
and you um yeah so realizing that and
understanding that perspective and
knowing that
everything that i went through was like
my choice
um and like you know now i'm making a
choice to
change from oh that happened to me like
well no i made
i let that happen to me i allowed that
to happen to me yeah i had something to
learn
from that so i i made myself i in order
to get where i'm at now i had to go
through that thing of course
right yeah yeah 100 yeah and so
having that kind of mentality has really
shifted from
oh for me all this happened to me too
like no it's okay like now
i am the person that i am i have the
depth that i have i can understand
you know so many other people who maybe
don't feel understood
um today in society um
and really need somebody to advocate for
them or like speak for them or
you know see through them and understand
that there's underlying pain and
underlying trauma that needs to be
helped healed because a lot of people
can do it on themselves but they also
need
somebody like pushing them so that's
kind of like my
um perspective and pushing gold to keep
me
out of the victim mentality is like my
purpose here isn't to
um like roll over and just let things
happen to me my purpose here is to kind
of go through all of that heal through
them and then allow the space for
other people to open up and heal as well
so
yeah beautiful yeah i love that i um
i think about my my i notice my victim
mentality
all the time like it's you know i've
been healing for
kind of uh generally generally saying
i've been on the path of healing
for the last couple years but i still
notice
recently like oh shoot my story behind
that
is stuck in victim mindset like i even
know so for example i've had a few
podcasts
these last few days in explaining my
like my story of like here's how my
childhood went childhood went
and um like sometimes even just trying
to explain what happened to me or
explaining
how my life went i fall into a victim
narrative
and i kind of question i'm like is that
is there a way that i could
you know not not deny that reality but
see it and maybe transform like how
could i even change
the wordings of what i'm saying to like
yeah this thing happened to me
but of course it had to happen because
now i can you know be
be in this position and i'll notice um
just as an example um that that pops to
mind
when i first started this work like you
know over a year ago
if i was explaining my situation when i
was in my teenage years i lived with
um a family friend who who for very
cheaply rented me her upstairs
room and so i kind of had like my own
little apartment up in her home
in explaining that over a year ago i
would have um
said like this this woman who um
you know like i've called her my nana in
my life
but this one like i would have called
her um also a hoarder
like because she had a lot of stuff she
had her own um things that she was going
through in her own life she had a rough
life herself
um but i would have i would have focused
on the fact that she had a lot of things
in her house
rather than like this was this like
very full of wisdom wonderful guidance
human being in my life like you know who
gave me a a place to live when i
sincerely needed it and who gave me
valuable advice all these things and i
would listen to myself
the way i'd be talking before i wouldn't
even realize that i'm almost like
trying to be more of a victim like yeah
when i was a teenager i had to live with
a hoarder
when in actuality like yeah some things
went you know i didn't get to live with
my family
in and that did suck but i got to live
with someone who like gave me very
valuable
life advice for the rest of my life who
showed me love
who let me into her home so even just
reframing
the stories that we that are not only
our internal narratives
um that we speak to ourselves but kind
of even the
the explanations of of our life and how
things happen to us
and who is the bad guy in this story
you know um so so that's how that's how
me personally
how i've i'm still changing my victim
mindset
mindset right you know i i i having this
podcast i hear myself
sometimes i'll still slip up and i'll
i'll say some things that are trying to
make me
you know sound or feel more special or
more like here's the reason why i'm not
showing up the best of my ability
because i have this thing that happened
to me and and we identify
with those things do you so so you're
you work with with a good amount of
people now and you've had more
interactions with
with different people who are on their
own paths what has been your experience
with um
other people shifting from their victim
mindset like is do you find
kind of like how the story i just
explained do you find other people
um stumble upon those sorts of things as
well like do they shift out of their
victim mindset in different ways
yeah 100 i definitely work with um
yeah like i work with women mostly
um yeah but yeah
they do it's it's like a but it's almost
like you have to
you have to like point it out you know
like not point out their victimhood but
like point out
that um like what i kind of rephrase is
like
you know we choose this life we kind of
choose what we go through um
but also you kind of have to point out
that like
you're able to to like shift
from this because that's kind of the the
perspective like we
when you're in victimhood you don't
realize that you're like in a victimhood
mentality
um until you have somebody be like okay
well like here's all this going on but
like here's the reality of the situation
um and that's kind of like yeah so
watching these women go from
well this is kind of the situation um
but yeah like i don't know it's just a
it's
really hard to explain because everybody
kind of like differentiates they all
have like their own trials and
they all have different perspectives but
yeah watching these women go from like
you know here's like all my trauma to
like wow i'm feeling really good
and i'm feeling really empowered and i'm
feeling really passionate and i'm
feeling like
you know i can do and i can shift and i
can change my mentality and i can
no longer sit in the poor me perspective
to uh
i'm gonna make [__] happen and yeah
that's cool you can really be
you know kind of the mediator of their
best self
or something like that you know they
they can tell you
here's what happened to me here's the
story and you'll be like okay that is
what happened that's
that's that is what's going on there's a
reality there
um is that reality helpful to you going
forward in the future
is there is there you know not just two
sides to the story but
um i don't know the word reframing is is
pretty powerful like when you can really
take a look at the things that hurt you
and the things that built you and the
things that
made you put up certain um put on
certain
bulletproof vests you know like
different armor that we all wear
different ego masks that we all wear
different versions of ourselves that we
feel need to show up in different ways
i think you can come to an age where you
you begin to ask yourself is this
helpful
is this something i want to hang on to
is this going to give me the life that i
truly want to live before i
before i you know leave my body and
and man that's that's super powerful so
how has it been
you know um we're definitely in the in
if i
put my foot in my mouth here definitely
correct me i don't know a lot of the
proper terminologies but
i do know that the uh we're in the age
of aquarius now right
so um along with a lot of this
from what i observe and from what i see
and like what i
when i focus on what a lot of like the
youtube content i absorb
we talk about the feminine energy rising
and to me that's super i i love
facilitate facilitating this i have a i
have a friend
my friend josh who was on the podcast a
couple days ago
he had explained to me a few weeks back
basically like
pointed out to me something i didn't
really notice um my vulnerability as a
male
um to to discuss these things he was
like it's very it's it's um i don't know
if you use the word important but
uh me he pointed it out and thanked me
for it
and said that it's good and and it will
help um
um you know facilitate conversations
that i think need to happen
so using my voice and my um my strong
though i'm a male i have strong feminine
energy or i have at least
some sort of understanding of it so i
see you know in the world this feminine
energy
rising up and i think it's it's like oh
of course we need it right now like it's
it's exactly what we need so
do you see um how do you see feminine
energy
and let's also how would you describe uh
for someone who is like what are you
talking about bro
feminine energy masculine energy like
what is that what are you even saying
like can you try to explain that to
someone who's never heard the
terminology before and then
where do you see it happening in our in
our world
yes okay i'm so excited that you brought
this up i love this
um yeah so for
first and foremost we have like our
inner child right
we have our maternal inner maternal and
our
paternal which is like feminine to
masculine energy so you have an inner
masculine
inner feminine energy within everybody
so the masculine energy is like a
the provider the caretaker the working
be
the busy like okay i got this you know
what i mean it kind of creates the space
for the feminine energy which is like
creative and flowing and like soft and
gentle and like still empowered but like
so they you know like yin and yang
like they work together they mesh
together they need each other to
um you know be whole and be complete and
be
really at peace um so when you have the
masculine
energy which is uh more like more
predominant i guess which is kind of
where the world has been
for many centuries it's really based on
a lot of ego a lot of like
intensity a lot of really i don't know
like not trusting the feminine um
a lot of like i don't
i don't know how to explain this other
than just like sharp tongue like just
really
really intensely sharp really intensely
like it's just yeah just like the most
egotistical i guess human being which
sounds kind of shitty to say
is like probably not in tune with our
feminine energy
and then when you have the feminine
energy that doesn't trust the masculine
energy
um you tend to like shove the masculine
down and that's where you kind of get
the push pull where
they're like going going going you see a
lot of women that are like going going
going and working really hard and trying
to like overcompensate for that
masculine energy
but they're almost like on a rat wheel
and they're not really getting anywhere
they're not really creating like that
abundance or like um
you know a lot of women feel stuck but
most of those women
um or men i guess i shouldn't stereotype
but
most of those women or men who um feel
stuck
tend to not trust their masculine energy
and they kind of need that to
like create what they're going for
create what they're doing i guess you
could say
um so now we're kind of anchoring that
in
um opening up that door to like feminine
energy and
um yeah that's kind of where the age of
aquarius comes in
um because we need it we've had a really
masculine world and it's kind of
led us to where we're at right now and i
don't know about you guys but
it's pretty shitty yeah we can't keep
doing just the only masculine thing
without looking at
our valuable resource of uh of balance
with feminine energy
of you know i mean we got to look at if
we continue to do things
exactly the way in which we have been
doing them do we have
optimal chances of survival and the
answer is literally known right now
i mean which we need to listen to and
say okay what can we
do differently like what voices in the
room can we
bring to the forefront to the to the
front of the table like
you know like it's it's time for the way
in which we've been doing things like
thank you you've served us well
but it's time for something new it's
time to listen to
new voices because we need we need
creative and
um creative
loving and gentle
new opportunities for our ways of being
as a culture as a society
but we also at the same time will say um
we need to not throw out the masculine
energy we need to be
we need to be assertive we need to get
our damn work done um we need to
uh we need to be strong but but i think
that
you know combining the the feminine
energy with the masculine energy
in our culture it just seems so apparent
how
how much power that will really bring us
like what's really this
this holding hands of divine
parts within human beings that were
we've for a long time just kind of
suppressed and kept down the
the feminine energy and so um for
someone listening who still has no idea
when we're talking about feminine energy
and masculine energy
um all males and females have masculine
and feminine energy it's like
like yin and yang ball i guess that's
what that's the only way that i can
explain it is like you just you need
them both but yeah
yeah and it's also like um super intense
too because
for like in order to kind of
spread that um we need a lot of
women but mostly men to be more
vulnerable
and be more open because as a site as a
society we have
ultimately let um men kind of
shut down like we shut men down for
having feelings for having emotions for
having
you know like opening up for being
creative for being
you know like okay go out in the field
go work
take care of your family provide um
but you know don't don't open up you
can't cry you can't like
express yourself or whatever you know
it's kind of viewed and that way and i
think that
anchoring in the feminine energy is kind
of opening up that doorway of like okay
you know men should express themselves
men and not
like this isn't just i guess batman but
as a society that's kind of what we've
leaned toward
um we've leaned toward like not allowing
them to express themselves but
yeah so i think that that's kind of
where we're heading in is like
empowering the feminine energy but also
allowing the masculine energy to like
open
up and feel really good about expressing
and releasing
because that's what we need is releasing
we need to shed we need to
dive deep into the shadow and the
emotions and whatever that looks like
um so yeah cool you just said shadow
let's talk about shadow work like what
is
what is our shadow i mean because we
have a you know
there's a collective shadow and that's
oh man that's like
that's a couple podcasts worth of
describing like how we're how we're
living alongside that and with that
uh within each of our psyches but um
shadow work so so these are these are
terminologies that
if i would have read four years ago i
would i would disregard them i would
brush them off i'd be like that's some
weird hippie [__] that i don't mess with
so like i i i want to try to connect
to my old foolish naive self
um like or people who are you know maybe
coming in
from that same location like i want to i
don't want to lose them here i want to i
want to keep them
um like like you know these are just
words to describe
things that uh belong within within each
of us you know with with
deep within our within our psyche in in
our consciousness
and um our our being as individuals
um in our being as a collective so
um words like like like shadow work
um how do we explain this to someone
who's
never heard any of these terminologies
before i'm sorry jc i'm giving you like
these
very difficult questions thanks for
hanging with me no you're totally fine
no i love it
um so shadow work is like the parts of
yourself that you don't see so that
can mean good or bad um most of the time
we
kind of and i say that quote unquote bad
there is no good or bad there just
is um that's like a whole other
perspective i'm sorry um but yeah
we it's good or bad
so it can mean like all of the
really good qualities that maybe like
other people can see you as but you
don't always see yourself as like you
kind of downplay your
good qualities um but somebody else
could explain to you like oh wow
like she's a superstar or he's a
superstar and they do this this and
they're like
i mean you looking at yourself you're
like oh wow okay like
i would have never viewed myself as that
or on the other perspective the
quote-unquote bad
it's like all of the things that you
have kind of shoved in your closet and
you
refused or like in your suitcase you
like refuse
have refused to kind of look at it or
have like not been able to see it
and so it's like unpacking like all of
your childhood trauma emotional trauma
um you know all the pain um because pain
is
energy but pain energy forms into
like reality i guess you could say so
like um you know stress
and um whatever stress comes out and
like knots in your shoulders so you
create that energy
um and so yeah ultimately it's like
massaging those out but like emotionally
i guess you could say
yeah i like that uh i i it's it's funny
i feel like you were
you triggered me right when you started
talking uh talking about shadow work
being
not only the things that you are ashamed
of the things that you're
you know you know that are that are in
your past that you don't like to look at
that when you bring it back up it's
painful to look at
because i i went through a lot of that
like where i'm like trying to make
myself face myself from before
but i still work you know i i'm still
actively
the the shadow work side of um
self-worth in absorbing compliments and
um listening when people say say thank
you or like
you know the message is when people are
like wow thank you for
making that video or thank you for
saying this on your podcast that really
helped me or thank you for sharing this
post or whatever like i still have a lot
of trouble with that and
um that's interesting that's cool to
call it shadow work too
because those are things that i actively
struggle with like i've
i've looked at my demons i've um you
know i've i've gone toe to toe with
those guys those
the the things of my past i've made i've
made um
amends in my own psyche i've accepted
things
from my own past within my own self but
in
in the in the present when it comes to
um just
believing people you know we we talked
the other day about imposter syndrome
just believing people when they say like
thank you or like hey you helped me or
or whatever
and not immediately thinking like well
if
if you knew me and you knew all my
deepest deepest darkest secrets you
wouldn't be thinking
you would hate me like there's still
that you know that that i work with in a
and i try to be
gentle and kind to myself um but it's
not always easy you know i try to notice
when it happens but sometimes it gets by
me and i
end up self-loathing for three hours you
know so
um imposter syndrome too i feel like we
could work that in in here
have you ever dealt with imposter
syndrome yourself good
lord like i that was actually
super like triggering for me because
like i've never put it into
words you know what i mean like that was
i've it's come up more frequently like
lately like you and like another girl i
follow on instagram posted something
about it so i think it's like
resurfacing for a reason um for not only
you know you and i individually but the
collective i feel like we kind of all
collectively go through
certain things um at the same time oddly
enough
um and so that's kind of something
that's popping up but yeah
going through imposter syndrome i
haven't really like dove
super deep into it but just from the
conversation the other day like
wow just to put like all of my worry
and anxiety and like you know
downplaying like that is
you know shadow work the good shadow
work i guess
um yeah that is like something i
definitely also need to work on is
you know seeing the value and who i am
and what i bring to the table um and
like how
just yeah just how i am as a person and
i really downplay that i really
over stress like i will say something
sometimes i'll say something in public
and i'll come home and
be like jace is that awkward like was i
weird saying that like
and that he's like no you're fine i'm
just like oh my gosh yeah
but yeah we convince ourselves of the
silliest things i
uh totally i um what is great is
is through through the community that's
being built and that has been built you
know like through the podcast and a lot
of us who are in the same area doing our
doing our work like you know you and i
will message each other with just like
flame emojis or like hey
keep going like that sort of stuff like
we you know this supportive
um of of our like inner healing friend
group who are who are people who are
trying to
like put on put on and um um help help
others
you know and uh i'll notice uh um
jay tsugawa she'll message me she is so
encouraging she's so positive she's so
sweet she like
she really she speaks right past my
[__] even through messages and just
speaks to my soul
and she's like hey this is awesome or
like hey you're great or like this is
beautiful or i love this side of you
or whatever and it's so hard for me to
listen to her sometimes
but but i i know that it's good and i
know that what she's saying is
is true but i'll have these guards up
where i'm like i'm not so good like
if you only knew me you know whatever um
i was actually gonna so
this um this mess i don't know if we
could see it here but this is the um
imposter syndrome post that we had
shared back and forth um
i was thinking what do you think about
me reading the caption do you remember
the caption being pretty profound
uh i didn't i just read like the actual
post that you posted
but please read it i would love to hear
it okay so so the post was uh it was
from a couple days ago from
anxietysupport.info this is on on
instagram and um
it's kind of kind of a lengthy um read
here but it's it's worth it so
when i was reading this i remember
feeling like
dude did they hack into my notes and
like copy this and post it on there
so um this is about imposter syndrome so
imposter syndrome is a psychological
pattern where a person feels
internalized fear of being exposed as a
fraud
my sense of self is unstable and i
always feel like my personality is just
a bunch of scattered fragments
the same fear plays in my head over and
over the fear that i have been faking my
entire personality and image
and someone finally looks beneath the
mask to uncover my true self
which is a bad person i keep having this
intrusive thought that i'm
faking being a good person and i'm
actually terribly selfish and cruel
and i'm just pretending to care about
other people logically i know that that
is very unlikely
logically i know that i'm just an
average person who tries to be as kind
as much as she can
but sometimes acts wrongly or says
something hurtful like most other people
do as well
but imposter syndrome tells me that i'm
terrible and it's just a matter of time
before everyone finds out and abandons
me
i struggle deeply to feel like i deserve
any praise or compliments or
achievements or successes
because i didn't work hard enough and
deep inside i'm not a good person
almost nothing feels earned or deserved
there's this looming feeling that
everything will be taken away when
people realize that i don't deserve them
if i get a job i feel guilty because i
think i tricked the employer into
thinking i'm capable
when i get a nice dm on here there's a
voice in the back of my head that says
they wouldn't have said that if they
knew who you really are deep inside
the more successes i have the more
intensely i feel that imposter syndrome
becoming louder
i have been practicing intense
self-compassion to alleviate my imposter
syndrome
i could tell you more about
self-compassion in my next post if
anyone was interested
in how i use it to cope with imposter
syndrome as well as my mental health
disorders
but yeah this is a little bit of how
apostle syndrome feels to me do you
relate how much does your imposter
syndrome manifest and what are some ways
you cope
so that's again from anxietysupport.info
i don't know the author i don't know
their name but
wow thank you to whoever took the time
to write that out and be so vulnerable
because
wow you know
reading that is just like it's it's so
um it just resonates so much you know
and i'm i am glad that i'm in a place
where it's not just triggering though
it's not just like oh
okay that's uncomfortable it's like oh
that's something that i
am still working on you know i can
almost hold space for myself
just in reading it because it's like
okay i'm not alone in this like there's
someone else who deals with this
as as well you know and um yeah i
mean i just really love that post i
totally had to read it yeah no i'm glad
that you did that was actually
like such a good read and such a good
perspective
um and it's really intense like that
intense feeling of like not feeling like
you're good enough and not feeling like
you're
or like you're yeah like you're showing
up and like not feeling like you feel
authentic but then after
the aftermath your anxiety kicks in or
imposter syndrome kicks in and you're
like
wait was that like where am i at what's
happening
you know what i mean like who am i yeah
i i think for me i um it shows up for me
in my comparison in myself now like i i
know you can't just say like no no
i'm a changed person so anything
anything shitty i ever did like just
doesn't it doesn't mean anything anymore
there's some extent of that but there's
also um
and maybe it's maybe it's a lot of kind
of like growing up in a small town area
like we have
um like we
i i'm so afraid that when people see me
now or they're watching this
like they only see me as who i was when
i was 22
and they're like i know that
[__] he ain't like that you know
what i mean
oh my god i cringe all the time
oh that's like my biggest yeah biggest
fear
i hear you oh well i i do get um
i do get enough messages in in people
who that does resonate with and they say
the same thing like a lot of people who
you know like i don't even know him that
well but we've met at parties or we've
seen each other at the bar or i know
them you know i've met them through
through me djing and being in the same
environments or whatever
and a lot of them will message me and
say you know
i deal with this too i've changed so
much that i
you you want when you when you meet
people or you see people who you used to
know
you you almost you want to control who
who you are in their eyes you're like
please don't see me as that person i
used to be because i've changed so much
that you're going to be talking to
someone who's not really here anymore
you know and um i i think that that
comes with a lot
a lot of healing a lot of self-worth uh
self-work and um you know
this is probably a process of of letting
that go like letting go
um what other people think about you for
sure but also
allowing yourself the space to just be
like i'm changed and as long as i know
it and i'm
i'm acting as if like that's that's
enough that's okay with me
they can think what they want um but i
would love the opportunity to prove to
them now
that i'm um you know more stepped into
myself
but 100 yeah
yeah it is it is i hear you i love that
that's like such a good perspective
yeah just being comfortable with like um
[Music]
where you're at what you're doing and
which is very hard for
our community and just our society in
general especially with like
comparison we have huge social social
media platforms
high expectations um that we
you know feel like we have to most of us
anyway feel like we have to kind of
upkeep with and like in reality like who
gives a [__] we don't have to do
anything we don't want to do
we you know compare ourselves and we
yeah just comparing ourselves to even
in the past which like the past isn't
even present so it doesn't you know all
that
that's another perspective of the power
of now like the process the past isn't
here it's not right in this moment like
it
it's not affecting this present moment
unless you allow it to affect this
present moment and like your mentality
so it doesn't really matter at the end
of the day
um and obviously no easier stuff than
done but that's something i always have
to kind of hold on to is like
uh i know who i am i know what i bring
to the table i know like all the change
in the growth that's really happened so
as long as i just keep continuously
showing up for myself like that's enough
and that's good
we're good to go it doesn't really
matter what you know
other people think yeah because if
you're you know you're kind of you
almost get stuck in the past when you're
constantly thinking you need to prove to
people in your past that you're not that
person anymore
you know yeah it's it's almost it's
almost a waste of your time like you
don't need to prove to anybody but
yourself you know you're the one living
your lived experience
yeah um so how do you use
in in your healing how do you use things
like journaling
meditation um like
um these active it's in its
i think it would also be important to to
maybe explain to people who
who don't do journaling or they don't do
meditation or they don't do um
you know even things like prayer even
things like um
positive affirmations listening to
positive affirmations on youtube
like the the work right to get our our
minds in
into an optimal loving state um
let's give the let's hear about your
your journey
with journaling meditation these sorts
of things and then let's try to give
like a
an elevator pitch to someone who doesn't
do these things like try to convince
them that they should
yeah um so my journey i don't know like
i feel like
my brain is like like it's always going
um and it's just like crazy so starting
out with meditation was
extremely hard for me and then it's also
funny because
my brain goes like this all the time
like i need to do this and this and this
but then when i sit down to journal
sometimes it's really hard for me to
like sit down and create
so i'm just putting this up front
because
a lot of the times people who don't want
to start
they sit down they're like well i can't
really meditate i'm not super good at it
or like i don't know what to journal
um yeah my process in that was
navigating and finding ways that it
worked into my life and not just like
the general population's life
and that's kind of what i preach
especially with my clients that i work
with
is um finding like certain
prompts for journaling to where it's
like easy
and you're kind of effortlessly like
they have like um
like journals that you can use that have
like okay tell me how you're feeling
about this on this day
so um i had to start using little things
like that to kind of get me motivated to
um you know write out my feelings in my
process
um on the journaling aspect for
meditation i started really slow
and i started doing like 10-minute
guided meditations because that's about
all i could sit down and do and one time
frame and one moment was just like 10
minutes out of my day
with somebody kind of guiding me through
it and talking me through it
now i can sit and listen to like certain
frequencies and i can sit for
a little bit longer than that um and so
that's kind of how that process went but
now
you know certain journaling like um i
keep i have so many different notebooks
randomly like throughout the house so
when i'm like thinking of something i
want to write down i can
you know just jot down like affirmations
or like if i need a little pick-me-up to
do something
um so yeah that's kind of like how i've
transitioned from like
you know wanting to do it to like okay
i'm doing it to like
okay yeah like i need to take time out
of my day like that's you know an
important aspect of my life
and has really helped my healing process
along the way so
yeah a lot of times we don't really know
what we need to say we don't know
what we think until we think it or we
don't know what we think until we
say it or we don't know what we're what
what needs to be said until it's said
those sorts of things we don't know
exactly sometimes you'll write
you're like have some sort of intuition
and you're kind of writing something
like it's kind of in this subject it's
in this area
and you write it or you write a half a
page you write just one paragraph or one
sentence
and you read it back and you're like wow
like i didn't i didn't realize i had
that in me i didn't realize i needed to
to get that
and it's not about it's not about
writing down things you know that you're
going to turn into your meditation
teacher and he's going to give you a red
ink pen grade like yeah b minus you
didn't really you didn't connect with
self very much when you
wrote that sentence it's uh it's it's
really for you there's no rules like
that that was a big thing for me was um
in in the basement at the old place
i mean i was like write anything that
comes to mind if it seems profound in
the moment allow it to be profound in
the moment
write it on the wall write it on sticky
notes write in your notebooks write it
on this paper
type it up whatever you got to do to get
it out
because it seems like a lot of the stuff
the the psychological burdens that we
carry when they're ready to be dealt
with
they come up and you can either have a
reaction that will kind of you know
maybe push it back down or like i'm not
ready to deal with this
or you can say okay this this feeling is
coming up and i'm ready to
allow it to come out i'm allow i'm gonna
allow it to
process in whatever way it needs to
begin processing and
a lot of times that means allowing the
the
allowing the words to fall out of your
fingertips you know and just
saying what you need to say and and just
saying what you don't realize you need
to say i think just sitting down
we're so fast-paced nowadays we're so
you know bite-sized
electronic like if you can pull out your
notepad on your phone and you can type
some stuff
excellent do it if that's what works for
you but
for me there was really something about
pen and paper writing down
journaling like free writing allowing it
to never be read
allowing it to never have to be
presented to people or be a certain way
it's crazy how healing that could be 100
yeah
no and i love that too and it's just
yeah but even in those moments though
sometimes i still like get cringy
with myself when you're like and that's
i'm just bringing this up because it's
human nature because sometimes we
sit down and we kind of anticipate and
not everyone but
um we anticipate journaling to be like
this really like beautiful like
um and it is in what it is but um
i guess just a different angle and a
different perspective like sometimes i
write things down and i'm like
like you know nobody's going to read
this or like
what are you doing like it can be pretty
gnarly but
like that's part of the healing process
and the part of
you know journaling in itself so oh yeah
you know that's actually a pretty
important
important thing to point out just that
you know we've used words like cringy or
like oh
you know we're describing that but i
think that really resonates with a lot
of people
man like i for example um
a few months ago um you know and i'm
still i'm still healing from this
i went through a big breakup and i
it's hard to know like where i'm at with
it it's hard to know where i'm at and
the healing of it it's hard to know
where i stand with it
and i've had a few times where i get
home from work and i'm you know
i'll um you know put some tunes on i'm
like let's just write
and the first thing that comes up is
like you know
dear ex-girlfriend you know what it is
not that you're going to send it to her
or or whatever it's just kind of but
i'll write a half page and be like oh my
god like if anybody ever read this it's
just embarrassing and it's just
cringy is the perfect word but when it
comes to healing
i mean i i remember when i first began
when i was dealing with a lot of
um um suicidal thoughts and i was
dealing with a lot of self-loathing and
really just was not liking the person
that i was being
um i sat down and i'm like what the [__]
is going on
and once i started inserting positivity
or i started um
allowing these things to come out or it
it all felt fake it felt fickle it felt
like it was fabricated
i was like what am i doing thinking i
could do some sort of spiritual work
like what the hell is this spiritual
stuff
it feels so fake and it i think it goes
right in hand with that cringiness that
we feel
you know um that that like
who am i to heal who am i to deserve
this healing who am i to write something
who am i to write a
letter to my ex that she'll never read
to help heal
you know i i think these are very human
things that come up
what do you think like have you
experienced anything like that
oh 100 yeah yeah and i think the
like behind the scenes like your your
being your soul like your whole identity
in that moment
um is like rejecting the new identity
that you're creating and yeah
and so like when you're like um
like rewriting i guess your identity
because ultimately that's like what
you're doing
you're like your body naturally wants to
be like
no like i'm i'm comfy i'm sitting here
i'm comfy in this
you know semi-misery um just because we
don't feel
worthy of being that positive without
uplifting that
whatever which is also in itself child
it's all childhood trauma like
everything that we do in our everyday
lives is all
stem to how we were raised and what that
looks like
um so yeah that's just another
perspective so every time
you're like cringing you're like i'm
just think like
i'm you know rejecting this change and
that's okay but you know what i'm going
to just keep going through it and moving
through it
so yeah yeah almost forgiving yourself
like okay that's that thing
popping up let's just allow it like
let's let's allow it to pass because
this is part of the
part of the the story this is part of
the process um
when it comes to things like childhood
trauma i think we should talk more about
that because
you know i i i try to put my put myself
in the shoes of
of like sometimes i'll be you know
going pretty in-depth i'll explain kind
of what happened to me when i was a
child or like here's how
here's what here's a part of my drama
here's a piece and then i think like
you know if if my mom were to be
listening to this episode which my mom
doesn't listen to this but
if she were like what i the way that i
explain things
you know it's hard to to come to terms
with it i'm like i you know i'm not
trying to insult her i'm not trying to
um you know point out like this is all
that you wear to me was only these
terrible things you know to my parents
because there's a lot of loving things
and now i totally just see like
oh you were just you know you were
loving me to the best of your ability
like you were raised by
family you were raised by parents who
have their own collective
trauma who who taught you things that
they thought were the best for you at
the time
and they just didn't work out and for
the for the trickle down
um so because
because i think i think everybody kind
of has childhood trauma right
in a sense like you you have things that
you learned at
um very uh
pinpoint times in your life in your
psychological development as a
biological human being
that trained you to be certain ways or
learn
i've used this example before you might
be afraid of snakes today
because when you were six and a half a
dude with a snake on his shirt
yelled at you you know and and
you could say oh that's childhood trauma
this guy this nature traumatized me and
it's not about
finding the victimizer because then you
get stuck in being a victim
that's not what childhood trauma is
about it's about
recognizing the the the patterns um
that are no longer serving you in an
adult that were taught to you
as a child correct me if i'm wrong there
that's kind of what childhood trauma
brings to me what does that sound about
right to you jc
100 yeah yeah and it is a kind of a
like fickle thing when you're navigating
through it all and you like don't want
to offend your parents but
what's that there's like a post or a
phrase or saying that's like
you can have um
like trauma and still like like
childhood trauma
like you know issues with like your
parents or whatever and still love them
and respect them for who they are today
like those two
can correlate and like live comfortably
together
um just because you have your trauma
doesn't mean that you completely view
you know the other person in the
situation or whatever that's completely
bad
it just is something that happened to
you and it's okay to express that and
communicate
and navigate through that trauma however
you please
um and to not allow easier said than
done
not allow that fear of like hurting
somebody else
um moving through your trauma
i guess yeah wow yeah that's that's
something that we definitely come
come up against um and then you know we
change our story about it as we heal it
or we change
um uh you know at least our perspective
about it and our the the
the narrator of our everyday life that's
playing in our head begins to form
new opinions but at the beginning it
does feel fickle it feels fake
it feels um impostor-ish it feels um
it feels like uh to me sometimes it
feels like blame
like i'm trying to find someone to to
blame
for why i suck at this thing you know
uh why i suck at this thing now is
because
i was hurt when i was five and and that
helps me justify why i continue to do
these bad behaviors or something
and and that's not exactly the way to go
no no so there's like there's two ways
to go about that too so there's
justifying it
and then sitting in it and being like
that's just the way i am
you know what i mean like this happened
to me when i was younger and i feel like
that's kind of justifying it but there
is
also a really empowering feeling and
realizing and recognizing where that
stems from
um because that's ultimately how you can
release your childhood trauma is
finding it at the base and like i always
elaborate this way like
with going in blowing it up um there's
still going to be little particles
around that you kind of need to sweep up
as you go but
that's kind of like how you navigate
through childhood trauma is like going
through
so i there's like the victimhood where
you just kind of sit in it or there's
like the growth mindset we're like yeah
that happened to me i'm aware that
happened to me but that
um i'm also aware that i'm capable of
you know blowing that trauma up and
releasing it
and like shedding those layers and um
you know empowering myself within that
trauma um
redirecting my you know pathways or
timelines
from you know past to present so
okay let's do um uh i have a proposition
for you what what if i
i come to you um so so say i'm i'm i'm
one of your clients
um you picked up a mail client and i
i come to you and um we have our
one-on-one session
and i say basically like i can't stop
thinking about the fact that
um let's say for an example let's say i
was i was sexually abused when i was a
child
and it has affected me as as a
20-something year old male
and it's part i think about it every day
and
i hate the people who did it and blah
blah blah
so say i come to you and i'm like where
do i start how can i
how can i forgive them how can i let go
of this
need to hold on to that part of my story
um obviously this is like very intense
you know this is not a blanket statement
you can give everybody who's gone
through these situations but
if you were someone if i was someone who
i'm like i'm ready to
i'm ready to meet the challenges i'm
ready to do the work i know this is
painful i know this is
this is deep but uh i'm ready to tackle
this like
what do i do jc what do i do what do you
do okay
so perfect that is something that i do
like to work with people
um is actually sexual trauma so child
determined sexual trauma
um but yeah so i mean it would be over a
course of time
so i do offer you know like different
time frames of courses
obviously to the comfort of each person
that comes
to me what they feel like doing um
but for that it would be like an ongoing
process where we would kind of meet like
this i have zoom calls with
my clients or facetime whatever um
and there's like a few different
dynamics that you can do ultimately
um that kind of lies in like your
like sacral chakra because that's kind
of where like your
sexuality your you know for women that's
like your womb area that's where
all of that trauma lies and then
ultimately up to your solar plexus too
which is like your confidence and
why not because your confidence
obviously drops down
um in that dynamic too so your lower
three chakras are ultimately
um like distorted
kind of you know traumatized um you're
ungrounded
you're dealing with sexual ones and then
you're dealing with like your confidence
and so
with each of those i navigate in like a
different dynamic for each of those um
but i would probably start with
expressing that because a lot of people
who come to me don't know
about where those lie because your
trauma each different trauma lies in
different
areas of your body um and then
expressing that giving them
certain exercises and activities based
off of
you know each chakra what um what they
need what i feel like they need the most
will kind of go through
each day with each you know different
one
um and then another thing that i do is
um i have like a guide i've recorded
this
myself i have like a guided meditation
where i kind of
make you face um the person
that's hurt you um yeah and you sit
like in a room and you um
i guide you through and allow you to
express
by closing your eyes express how you
want to speak to that person how you
want to
um let your anger out um you know you
can like
hit pillows you can hit whatever the
case may be just kind of like really
releasing all of that anger
um frustration you know i i do this too
myself um you know you end up crying you
end up really just being like really
empowered
and then at the end of that i have kind
of like an inner child activity
um exercise um where you kind of like
speak
to your child in like the time frame
where
that trauma happened um and just kind of
like
spiritually and energetically supporting
that child and showing up for them
in a way that you maybe didn't get like
protection wise because
you know sometimes situations like that
happen and you aren't rightfully
protected or
um you know just telling them that it's
going to be okay
and that life you know life gets better
and that you
ultimately are going to heal um yeah
so that's kind of just a few different
ways that i navigate very lightly but
but yeah yeah yeah so you bring up so
it's
it's essentially sounds like you know
you get it's like okay
this person who experienced this tough
thing when they were younger
um they're ready to to you know attack
it they're ready to face it they're
ready for
to for they're ready for the next step
in the healing process
on the healing path um whatever that
looks like for them as individuals
so you're going to get them in a safe
environment
to basically you know bring back up that
thing
but also you know where are our you know
amygdala and our brain stem response
when we think about those things you
know our heart rate increases our palms
get sweaty
um knees weak vomiting on my sweater
already
sorry um but our you know we are that
biological response like we can all feel
it you know when you think of something
traumatic that happened to you a lot of
times it's
um you know like if you deal with
intrusive thoughts like those come up
and you're like
like ugh like it's another little
cringey sort of thing but
when you can when you can slowly softly
with love with space
with the support of of a guide to
bring those bring those back up in a
safe environment and say like okay you
know i
i recognize my body is is initiating
this fear response
it is it is trying to you know my my
biological vehicle is attempting to
relive this to some extent
but it's okay i'm in a safe spot um i'm
relaxed i'm
i'm here like let's look at this as my
adult version of myself
let's talk to my to my six-year-old
version of myself
man that's so powerful and i will say um
i haven't done
i haven't done your guided meditation jc
but
i have had experiences i may have talked
to you about this before but
um it's been over a year now but when i
was going through this i had some
periods of
just i mean i was i was taking i was
doing crazy amounts of yoga tons of
breath work
lots of meditation um lots of like
hypnosis um
just smoking a lot of cannabis a lot of
cbd
nootropics i was in another dimension
basically trying to heal
all this stuff um but i i actually had
pretty profound
um you know a rather euphoric
you know psychedelic experience um by
listening like listening all these
frequencies and stuff and
and um obviously like you know good good
amounts of marijuana in the right
settings in a right very very safe
environment
i had my speakers on the floor like
right next to me doing like
deep yoga stretches for hours and hours
um
and i had i don't think this is how
everybody would experience it you know
like i was i was under under the
influence of
quite a few things in in a sense you
know
just like with nootropics and cannabis
and this in the the
um sounds and all this stuff breath work
but
i i basically visualized my younger self
like my
like teenage yourself actually um
and basically had like a little
unplanned
ceremony that that happened of me kind
of i i saw
and again this isn't like you know god
walked into my room and i saw him clear
as day as you you and i
like i'm i was aware that it wasn't um
um the same physical here and now
reality this was a psychological
experience but i basically kind of
saw my younger teenage year self in the
room with me
i had a long crying session i thanked
him for for the man that he was
in in the the armor that he put on to
survive the things that i was going
through at that time
um and it was basically this like i got
out of my own way
and i thanked this younger version of
myself and i said i
i got this from here though it's it's
okay like you we can take off that armor
it's okay
i got you from here so i basically
showed up for my younger self as a grown
man
and it psychologically helped me
massively like it
it turned on things it healed things
within me um it was it was a profound
experience and i
and i uh through a lot of that area i
now consider it's like oh like i had
around this time is when i have like a
spiritual awakening um
which is you know an intense terminology
it's an intense word it's like
again if i would have heard this years
ago i would turn off this podcast right
now because
like that's some weird [__] that i don't
mess with but uh that's how it was for
me i had an awakening
of of my true self and i um i healed my
my younger
um you know childhood wounds that were
really affecting me in many ways
and i'm still working on all these sorts
of things but that was a pretty profound
one um
yeah i think you know people have their
own versions of access to this
and it's it is very healing and i think
it's super great that you offer
you offer a doorway a pathway for other
people with that
yeah yeah thank you wow that's super
powerful and that's so cool and that's
something that um you know a lot of
people
trouble like have trouble navigating
through it's like really facing that so
props to you for being able to kind of
sit in your own space and be like okay
this is what i'm doing that's what i got
going on but
it is really powerful and yeah also
forgiving yourself too like your
childhood self for
like you know being like the person
like you had to wear that armor until
you couldn't you know i mean like you
have to put on those
coping mechanisms and protect like
protecting yourself to a sense and
um yeah like it is an important role and
an important factor
um to be able to grow and be
who you are today going through your
spiritual awakening like wouldn't have
had a spiritual awakening if you didn't
have that armor that you needed to kind
of like
chisel away like you said you know what
i mean yeah
exactly yeah oh man it's uh
well it's it's actually you know i will
say just uh just putting a pin in where
i'm at like it's it's beautiful to
actually be able to express that
more clearly now like as time passes in
in this experience for me um becomes
more in my rear view mirror
i'm able to process what it really did
for me you know and it'll be interesting
to see like if i
you know if i'm sharing that story in 10
years like maybe
like like what's this going to look like
how is it going to reframe the person
that i am
yeah i love that also i wanted to add
two
just before we like transitioned into
the next
um but when you have like sexual trauma
too you tend to whether it's with a male
like or a female whoever
whatever that happens you tend to have a
wound within
your like masculine or feminine energy
too so a lot of the times like as a
woman going through sexual trauma
you tend to that's where like beating
down the masculine energy internally
comes in and then you overcompensate
without feminine energy
um just wanted to throw that out there
that kind of all correlates together
just so you know
definitely yeah i think that's probably
an important piece i bet you that that
sentence right there will probably speak
to it to quite a few people um
okay so so if the the situation we just
expressed the situation we just talked
about
of course they can contact you you have
a website and they can um
if they're ready to process these things
and they're getting the right vibes from
from um speaking with you or seeing you
on here they can reach out to you but um
what are what are some other off top
your head like what are some resources
if someone's
like wow okay maybe i'm ready to
experience that like that sounds
like like i i think i'm ready to to face
those things i want to heal these things
like where would be
what would be your suggestion for a
starting point someone who just wants to
kind of
start diving into these things or dip
their little toe in the water
what do you think where would we send
them where would we send them
um i would just say
i don't know like i feel like as corny
as it sounds sometimes like instagram
really does have a lot of
um like platforms and opportunities for
you to kind of like read and deep dive
into
the underlying like traumatic
experiences and like the emotional
um position behind it um but yeah
there's
like a i don't even know there's so many
that i fall i couldn't even pinpoint
them but just
starting and you know finding hashtags
that kind of correlate with like what
you want to heal
um you know any things like spirituality
if that's like something you're one of
wanting to dive into it's just like
awakening hashtag awakening
you know sexual trauma hashtag whatever
typing those in and
finding like certain pages that really
correlate with um
you know what you're feeling like your
vibe um
because my vibe and the pages i follow
can be completely different from
you know the next person's uh
yeah yeah yeah so kind of like tr
trusting what you're you know because a
lot of these like i've
like i've said multiple times already
you know a lot of these the words and
the terminologies and the
you know um a lot of the the more
spiritual words are
to someone who's very unconscious to
someone who's very um
set in their ways who's not like kind of
kind of open in into
or ready to ready to hear it rather
a lot of the the terminology and the
things that are said on some of these
accounts are
a little like oh that doesn't resonate
with me i don't get that i don't know
what they're talking about you know but
as you reframe and you learn what these
words mean and what they might mean to
you as an individual
then you can you can flip that
perspective so i i think you're totally
right i think that was a great example
instagram you know that's something that
i did um i took a br i had taken a break
from social media during that time when
i was healing
when i came back i was like i want to
you know if i'm going to have these
little dopamine addictions which i
certainly do i'm totally addicted to
social media just like everybody else
but i i was like let's at least make it
to
where if i'm mindlessly scrolling for
five minutes
it's some positive affirmations it's
some some
uh info information about trauma it's
some
stuff to like uh trigger my ego to where
i'm like oh okay i'm thinking this you
know so
yeah following these pages um i really
like to
i i would watch guys like joe rogan i
watched a ton of joe rogan and
his guests if i liked them or they
seemed healing i would follow them and
check out their account
i'm like oh they got a book i'm gonna
i'm gonna read that book or i'm gonna
follow their instagram and
so yeah just i i exactly like what jc
said follow your bliss man like
start making your daily habit of
scrolling through social media scrolling
through instagram
um follow follow more
accounts that that speak to like the
future version of you
and that speak to in in in that that
that show up
um you know with soft words for the the
inner child within you we all have our
own inner child and you know sometimes
it needs to be spoken to and instagram
is a great resource for that
so yeah 100 and then i feel like it kind
of spirals
from there like that's just a good
starting point and then you know
researching certain books that you want
to read if that's something you want to
dive into and then
starting slow that's like my my biggest
advice that i could give to anybody like
wanting to start their healing journey
is like don't overwhelm yourself with
like all of the things at one time like
start with instagram start with reading
one book
start with doing a 10 minute meditation
start with a guided journal
start with you know all of the little
things that like
can make up maybe even you know 30
minutes of your day
um and like not because that's
i think where we get lost we tend to get
lost as human beings and like starting
this is we were like what's going on i'm
stuck i don't know what i'm doing and
it's like
yeah we tend to overload our plate like
we have to do all the things and we have
to be good at them we have to do them
all right now like
that's not the reality of the situation
you just have to start and start small
start somewhere so that that's really
important actually because someone like
me i am
like i get obsessed with things i like
i'm all in like when i started doing
this healing stuff i'm like
yeah if i'm awake i'm listening to
content about healing my childhood
trauma like i'm
all in i'm doing i'm gonna do yoga for
six hours today or i'm gonna
i'm gonna try to meditate for as long as
possible like and that's not the way for
everybody so that i i love that you said
that i think it's very important that
you said that
match where you're actually at like if
you're not i'm just like a
intense dramatic person i just i do
things differently like i have to just
go all in it's just
it's if i just become like into this
obsessive loop about it and
you know if that's not healthy for me
that's on my own to figure out but
um i get definitely i think that's a
very important thing
like take take one step at a time like
if you if you don't have enough
uh i like dr jordan peterson talks about
these sorts of things like
if you know say say you're at a point of
like i need to make a list
for what i need to do today or i need to
make a list of things that need to be
taken care of this month
and you just you're you're like it's so
overwhelming i can't do it like i can't
make the list i can't think of all these
things
well what can you do i can go to my desk
i can go to where i write and i could
set out a piece of paper with a pen on
top of it
and then okay let's let's walk around my
room let's read my book let's play some
video games whatever whatever your thing
is
and then like okay well what what else
can i do what do i have the energy to do
i'm gonna walk over there and i'm gonna
write one thing i'm not gonna get my
whole month schedule done
i'm gonna write one thing though you
know it's like you can't make your whole
bed
well hey pull your covers over you know
make it look kind of made then you know
that's so important and i'm really glad
that you said that jc work
work where you're at 100 yeah and that
is something i also
like tell clients that i work with
because i try to not overwhelm them
because it is really overwhelming
sometimes
um navigating through things and yeah
starting with like you said like a small
list
right like one thing down or if you feel
like you can do more than that write
like three things down
do them and then finish do a couple more
things on the list
and then do those then kind of move to
that but also one thing
um i do want to add to that is when you
dive into the spiritual reality
um we tend to look at
so many different dynamics we have like
they're really really spiritual people
which i love and appreciate them for who
they are
and then we have the you know the kind
of new like
just dipping their toe in like don't
really know what's going on um and i
also want to point out that
for some people i had it i struggled
with this for a long time because i felt
like i was like
you know not new into it at this point
but i'm also not like super
like well quick i mean i am but like i'm
not super like spiritual which i'm okay
with and i you know respect the people
for who they are but i almost felt like
i had to live up to
a certain spiritual standard and then
i've talked to a friend
girlfriend recently and um we've kind of
come to this conclusion that like
you can be extremely intuitive and
really
like psychically smart and spiritually
intelligent
and also still be like a human being and
want to do nice things for yourself like
have nice clothes have nice hair have
nice
stuff all in the same swing you know
what i mean and as a woman
you know living up to certain societal
standards and men too
like living up to certain societal
standards um
and then correlating spirituality into
that we kind of think like whoa as a
spiritual being like i should not want
to do any of those things like i should
just want to
live in a cabin in the woods and have no
power and like not do my hair and like
you know not shave or anything and it's
like i mean you can
have the same intellectual spirituality
as that person but also
want to you know have nice things so
being a human being
is what i like to say because being
spiritual is like
so alien form and being
a human being like we came here to be a
human being so
be a [__] human being and correlate
your spirituality into that and
live it up man live your life yeah yeah
yeah i love i love that you said that
too a lot of these things are
um the uh in the meditation world
you can be like you know you're you're a
monk meditator and you wear robes and
you
you live in the tibetan mountains or you
could be a householder
like you you meditate and you care about
your conscious awareness but you're a
householder you own a house you live in
in the modern age and then another one
that resonates with that that i've been
saying
non-stop lately because i just love it
and it's been huge in my life
is uh it was from either timothy leary
or ram das but i heard ramdas
repeat it and it's uh always remember
your buddha nature and your social
security number
isn't that so great that's so valid
that's so real
because it is like today like i mean you
can go
however which way you please and respect
to anybody out there who
goes on whatever journey or pathway they
choose but yeah like we are still
thinking
we do stop a social security number we
do kind of still have to plug into the
matrix and we
you know we do have to also step
out of that and put ourselves before any
of that in the same thing so
and i think that's huge for for things
like grounding you know and
our lower chakras i think that that's we
we do need those things we have to
you know um i'll find i've definitely
been one to be
you know really locked into my my high
rep chakras and my feet are dangling way
off the ground i'm just way up up in my
zone and it's like
oh it's you got to get grounded man i
mean there's times in our lives and
especially me as a creator i think there
is times where it is good for me to
escape into the ethereal realm of of the
crown and third eye chakra but
um you know coming back down to reality
and
remaining grounded is what's the good
homeostasis that good balance
um yeah that's so so those things are
they're all important you know
your buddha nature and your social
security number very important
um jc i would love to switch over to i
sent my homie last night
um i have one of my one of my good
friends um one of my like close
childhood friends
he's been going through a lot of his own
healing lately
um he's been you know you know reading
some new books and
um you know do doing the work he's
really diving in and he's doing so great
and last night i sent him um the 16
personalities
um quiz and uh you know i was so excited
to hear his response and i'm like oh
what are you like what's uh
um i think he was a uh intp is what he
landed on but
you and i miss jc are both infjs
and for me uh
again this is something years ago that i
would have been like oh
okay so that's like i'm going to take
that about as serious as i take
our position on planet earth versus the
stars around us in astrology and like
there's things that i never took serious
before i never
just because i didn't know anything
about them i i was
my judgments of these things were based
off of a position of no knowledge on
them so i was just
i felt comfortable in thinking i knew
anything about it by
never exploring into it so learning
about um
you know taking personality quizzes and
it asks you a certain um
set of questions and then it gives you a
personality type and when i read my
personality type when i read the
the infj i started watching videos about
it i
legitimately cried like i i i i felt so
like i've always um you know i've always
felt like black sheep i was very black
sheep in my family but also
um i'm i'm i'm aware of my black
sheepness
amongst you know even my my friend
groups where i feel
i belong very much and they make me feel
loved but i i do feel very different
than them
in reading the infj i was like
wow i feel i've never understood like
nobody's ever
understood me like this this is
describing how my thought process goes
i feel so i felt validated and in
healthy ways
what tell me about your journey um into
the
the the infj realm the 16 personalities
realm um
and then do you recommend to other
people to take personality tests and
dive into that
oh my gosh yes please yeah it
i mean honestly it was just reassuring
because like not only for yourself but
especially like the people surrounding
you
um it just gives you a better
understanding of where you're at who you
are who you were born
to be um and then the people surrounding
you
like who you're born to be um like if
you're having you know certain conflicts
in your friendships for a certain
conflict in your relationships or with
family
that is also something that you can like
include in that so you're
seeing them for who they are and what
they offer and like
their personality dynamics so how they
communicate how they present
themselves how they show up um it kind
of all runs through
most of that um so yeah
it was a it was very cool to read about
i like
i don't know i feel you on that i've
i've never been to
i'm gonna kind of step into victimhood
but it's fine
um i've always had a really hard time um
making the right kind of friendships the
right kind of dynamics i've always been
the
codependent relationship person i'm
gonna own that
um i've always been in relationships for
as long as i can remember
um and that's just you know part of my
healing and part of my process is
going through that and understanding
being aware of my codependency
um but yeah and i've always had a really
hard time making
long lasting standing healthy friendship
dynamics
i've had you know friendships that i've
been close with but i was either you
know like
partying and using or i'm just in a
really unhealthy mental state
you kind of attract a very similar
dynamic
of the person like mirroring you um
and so you know what on no one's fault
like we just
you know fall apart we you know you know
turmoil emotional turmoil happens
friction happens and then
you know you're no longer really
speaking or it's just not how it used to
be
um which is growth but um very accepting
of that
but yeah so being an infj
i've personally it helped me realize
like
i'm very introverted i'm very quiet i'm
very to myself and very in my thoughts
and varying my feelings
um and it is a very rare personality
type very very rare but it's like two
the top there's like two percent of the
world or something like that
yeah yeah and so you know i'm a very
like i love to connect with people who
are just like me
um which is really hard on myself
because i have such high expectations it
just bites me in the ass
um and so it's yeah it's allowed me to
see
that um i don't have to disconnect
because it is such a rare um personality
type like i don't have to just connect
with like my personality type like
that's all ego based um
i can connect with other personality
types and see them for who they are and
accept them for where they're at
but yeah help me move through that
process because before i'm just like for
me why do i not have any friends that
are just right there with me i don't
understand
um what's happening what's going on and
i'd actually like
get emotional about it like cry like so
often
but now i'm at a space where i'm like oh
you know that's cool that
i don't meet a lot of people who are
like me um and i can accept and love
you know these new people walking into
my life or old people
that are still in my life for who they
are and see them at a different light so
yeah yeah it's pretty powerful stuff
isn't it like you can really
i think you know not only learning
not only learning about yourself like
there's that validation of of um
which which i think this is probably
like healthy a healthy amount of
validation self-validation um because
that's always a tricky subject with
self-validation especially with like our
world of social media and
acting out um trying to be impressive
but uh
you know learning about yourself
learning about
because once you can kind of observe the
way that you think and the way that you
process things
it allows you to realize in a very
profound
present uh here way uh that
other people are coming to their own
conclusions and their
their like other people of other
personality types
are not thinking the same way as you
like they're
experiencing a different a different
perception of of reality because
their internal dialogue in the way in
which
they um perceive the world around them
in the conversations around them and
then
run it back through their own self like
it's a different process than you
and you're doing this magical thing of
like relating to them
and talking to them and it's really
impressive like with how different we
we we're so so similar in so many ways
but
you know when you read the 16
personalities in a lot of these
differences
up here we're pretty different how we
how we form opinions of
of the world out here so it's it's
absolutely wonderful that we're even
able to
so properly connect and and discuss
things you know
yeah i love it it's yeah that's awesome
but
yeah you're absolutely right how we
navigate it's like different lenses
every person has a different lens that
they see and
hear the world in and yeah and that's
where you know a lot of conflict comes
from and
what is it like the four agreements like
you know expectations you kind of expect
people to
think and navigate how you think and you
kind of just have to
love and understand like the person for
their viewpoint their perspective
they're bringing value into your life
and so
yeah that's uh it is crazy to think
about because you know like you get
like me personally like i get so
frustrated sometimes i'm like
gosh like i would do this this way like
i don't understand why they're not doing
it this way
and it's like well i mean they have a
completely different brain they're using
probably a different portion of their
brain
and especially from male to feminine
like male to female
we think and navigate differently and
then this is another perspective too is
like i'm left
left-handed and so um most right-handed
people use the left side of their brain
and
left-handed people use the right side of
their brain so navigating in that way
too like that's another
perspective is like um yeah and
ultimately we're all just using
different portions of our brain and how
we see the world and
right yeah yeah we're we're under this
um
i mean like really not question a a
perception that everybody is kind of
living and
we all just live in the same shared
reality and and we all act the same and
we all have the same emotions like
like we all experience we all have
access to be able to experience
the the plethora of human emotion but
the way in which we approach it the way
in which we dissect it the way in which
we
um experience it as it's happening and
before it's happening
it's all different you know we're all
the all the synapses are are you know
firing in the same way but the way that
the story is being
you know centered and um
formed you know to form our personality
and our responses and our reactions
it's different and it helps you i think
it helps me
actually be even more compassionate
towards other people because you know if
i can see
if someone's if someone's patient enough
to like you know bear with me as i'm
stumbling through my
thought process like i should certainly
be doing the same for them because
they're not doing it the same way that i
am but they are getting to
their conclusions through some sort of
way that i don't understand from
first-hand experience so i've gotta
i've gotta be willing to leave room for
that i've gotta make some space for them
and give them some time to
express themselves you know 100
yeah yeah wow
i know moving through like that that was
like such a big healing too because like
i don't know about you
i mean i'm sure you've kind of brought
it up but like i am so like
nitpicky and controlling um but not in
like a
overwhelming way just like i'll notice
somebody doing something and i'll
think internally like oh man i can
totally do this this way like why
you know why are they not doing it that
way i did that but like stepping back
keeping my mouth shut and just
understanding that the process is going
to be different that's like one thing i
really had to heal through because i
would be like
what are you doing like we can do it
this way um but now like stepping back
and be like
okay it's fine like there's more than
one way to
you know drive a car or walk on the
sidewalk or
you know what i mean yeah and that way
you don't like step on what people are
valuable for like you can really
like allow them to shine in the light
that only they they can shine
and i think that's super valuable yeah
so i
i would recommend to anybody like check
out the the personality types um i know
there's
there's 16personalities.com or whatever
it is
um in in and then there's
oh man there's humanmetrics.com that's
another one and that's the meyer briggs
who is um um
i think i think carl young had to do
something
with that i could be totally wrong but
meyer briggs i i think it was a mother
and daughter who who developed his
psychologist um i could be butchering
this so definitely like do your own
research but
it was uh it was like dude just
it's so funny just giving myself the
time to like all right let's just fill
out this serp like
you know i felt like i was doing a a
myspace questionnaire
you know but answering these questions
and then you get your answer at the end
or you get
you know this paragraph of like so
here's what it seems like
based off of your answers this question
here's how you perceive the world here's
how you
feel here's something that happens to
you and i'm reading it like
what like wow this is profound and
it's it's very helpful and then um back
then
when i was in a relationship it was also
very helpful for me to to read about my
partner's
ways and so i could say like oh okay
here's how like when i'm standing there
wondering why the hell she's thinking
this way when i clearly just presented
the the truth of what everything
actually is
in this situation i can now say oh
she perceives her reality differently
than me like the way that she gets to
conclusions the way that she
reacts and and these are also things you
know scorpio libra cancer these sorts of
things
are also helpful for that you can
understand the person
that you're in relationship with more um
more more broadly you know not just why
don't you think exactly like me
because the way that i think is the only
way that is
you know yeah 100
yeah no and i definitely have done that
with jace too so he's like
i'm an infp and he's an enf or infj
he's an enfj so he's just like the
extroverted
version which i mean i mean i personally
need that in a relationship i'm so like
awkward and like quiet in public
settings and he just
shows up for that which i appreciate in
a tiny bit so yeah definitely
allowed me to like understand him as a
whole
yeah excellent i i would i would
recommend that to
people in relationships and people by
themselves definitely check out
16personalities.com
or humanmetrics um
or i mean there's a bunch of other ones
too and they're all super helpful just
explore whatever whatever talks to you
and then for me once i found my you know
infj i began listening to
um the personality podcast i think it's
called
um the uh
oh personality hackers podcast and
that's on youtube
and that was that was really good um i
sent that to my buddy
last night and he's going to explore
those but um we're getting fairly up
here in time i did want to talk about
um you you are
an intuitive empathic healer can you
explain to me like i'm i'm dumb tarzan
and i don't know what any of this means
can you explain explain it to me as if
that because um i feel
i it's it's it's beautiful i love that
you've stepped into this
i feel like once i started seeing you
use words like this and you know
starting to
um like your your your soul identifying
with these things more
to me as your friend and someone who you
know you were on my podcast at the
beginning i'm like yes
like that that seems that that resonates
with me i i see that in jc so
can you explain these terms intuitive
empathic healer can you explain that to
me
yeah okay so um i guess the easiest way
that i can put it is just like
it's i don't like using this word
because i feel like it's so like broad
and
you think of this word and you think
like like psychic right so like
channeling psychic you think of a
sidekick you think of like
going into a space and like paying
somebody and like
whatever they yeah and so
yeah i just like intuitive so like i
have just a long line of like
psychics and mediums and my family and
so
i've kind of been able to step into like
those gifts and so
um intuitive is just like that feeling
using you know channeling from um
you know i'm what is it called so
there's like different there's
clairaudient
clairvoyant clairsentience a
clairaudience like you can hear things
like you can hear spirit you can
i'm not that um clairvoyant is like you
can see things
visions um i get a little bit of those
um
and then there's clairsentient which is
just like knowing so like
knowing everything knowing things like
sometimes um
i'll just like it's almost like
computing um
like downloads i guess like you're
computing you're putting
you know code coding and whatever in the
computer and
it inputs information for you right so
that's ultimately i guess what i'm doing
for
my clients working with people um so
yeah sometimes people will just like be
talking or like
um they have like a certain illness or
they're not feeling good and i'll just
spit out like a random thing and i'm
like yeah i don't know where that came
from but you need it
um to heal so yeah and then there's
um there's a couple i think there's like
one more but i can't think of it
but yeah so um yeah that's kind of what
i do
um i've more so stepped into that
recently so
if it feels um it feels like uh
um man how do i word it it feels like
abilities that are outside
of ego identification right like it's
it's like a you know as an as an
artistic person um
i i was i was talking with a musician
friend on the podcast yesterday
and we were kind of talking about the
the process of creation and the process
of like writing music
and it's this you know to get in contact
with the muse or put your little
net into the the freeway of the muse and
try to catch something like let's catch
a lyric let's catch a song there
you almost you get out of your own way
like what you do mentally is like
you just become so present and you and
you you almost are able to turn off the
thinking mind so to say
and um you're you're listening to what
needs to come up
in in a um you know correct me if i'm
wrong but this seems like
kind of what what you would do and i'm
just trying to relay because i think
also as an infj i think the way that you
the way that you heal in you bring up
sorry i forgot the terminology that you
just used but
the way that you process what needs to
be heard or say what needs to be
said to you and your client i think is a
similar process to how i
attempt to like write raps or write
lyrics or create music
is i try to get out of my own way and
i'm like okay this is what needed to
to come up does that resonate yeah 100
like that's yeah like like channeling
like it's
almost like something comes over you but
in such a really fulfilling and positive
way
um and just kind of you like elbows deep
it just consumes you
and you know like you're just really
elevated and really happy and really
like
it you know like your purpose like what
you're supposed to be doing like
music is your purpose like you creating
stuff is your purpose and so you being
able to like
channel that and you know step into that
and just kind of have something take
over you like
that's why you're doing it you know what
i mean and so that's kind of where
um this dynamic comes from yeah just
allowing everything to shed being really
present
um and having you know channeling from i
call it source like it's just a source
to me um
but yeah i don't i don't know i'll stay
yeah no i i i think that that's that
sounds about right
um that is the
yeah it's a you know again again with
terminology we can expand on on even
things like source because this is
something that
again at the beginning when we started
this i was like what the [__] are you
talking about
but uh like source
god um the the vortex the
the um there's all these terminologies
that are actually like
the we we get caught up in these
pointless like no no it means this or
here's the right
word for this or here's the right you
know mouth movement that describes this
thing and it all needs to be the same
and
i think that what what you find um when
you explore in this area
is a lot of these a lot of these
terminologies are actually kind of you
know they're speaking to the to the same
thing um they're speaking to this
this something that's more divine within
you and um
it's not it's not like man in the clouds
god
it's it's um you know that's that's like
a
this is like our veggietale low-level
understanding of something that we
really haven't thought about it but we
never questioned it that much
we just like sticking to our guns and
like i don't believe in god because i
don't believe in a floating man in the
sky
and it's like no no but what about the
the source of all wisdom
what about the thing that makes
evolution do what it's doing
what about the thing that was before the
big bang what about the
the you know how does how the [__] does
an acorn know to grow into a wonderfully
beautiful tree
how does it know that like that's the
the source that the acorn is using
that's the the the by the biology
the evolution the whatever that is
telling that acorn to grow into a tree
is
um you know that there's a thing within
humans that's like that like that
there's a trueness there's a a rightness
relationship with
the the exterior world and it matches up
with our interior and our
our ego minds in our modern society have
really suppressed a lot of those so to
me i think that humans have
many abilities that we have lost
connection with
um we've forgotten we're we're a species
with amnesia in in many ways and i think
you know because of the internet and
because our advancement in technology
you know people like you and i are
are able to now you know connect with
the the the source within us the
the thing that just feels right and
we're going to trust it
and i i can't wait till we're you know
when we're 40 50 years old and we're
looking back at like now we've been able
to sharpen these things we've been able
to
learn how to really listen to that inner
voice you know we've stayed we've stayed
on the path and
i mean i'm i'm very looking forward to
and excited for
the future of all of this knowledge and
all this learning and all of this
you know hopefully helping other people
along the way too just imagine what
we're going to be able to do
in 40 50 years i like honestly couldn't
i couldn't even imagine at this point
like it's it's insane to even think but
yeah 100
agree with you um putting in the work
now i feel like is going to
you know for all of us as a collective
putting in that work now and really
tapping into because everybody's capable
of channeling
and tapping into um source whatever that
looks like
each person's different and that's
totally okay um
but yeah you're capable of just like
digging deep and really being able to
connect with like
your intuition and like what feels good
and what feels right to you because
ultimately like
that is our only real thing i feel like
is
you know you're solidified feeling good
and knowing like
what's right for you like you're the
only person that can
know what's right for you and know what
you need to be doing and know what your
purpose is nobody else can tell you
outside of that so yeah definitely
attuning your frequency to to
you're tuning your frequency to your
inner voice to your intuition
you know there is something that i mean
words can't express it but
it's it's it's a rightness it's a it's a
it's not even fulfilling fulfilling
isn't even the correct word but it's a
it's a it's a knowing of this this is
where it is
this is this is the thing in which i've
been looking for without
while unknowingly looking for it right
it's uh
it's uh yeah wow yeah there's a lot of
there's a lot of healing to be
to be had there and a lot of um
yeah just a lot of knowing i guess i'm
at a loss for words for a lot of it but
uh you know that's that's the funny
thing too is
is words these mouth movements these
agreements that you know
when i hold up a banana and i say banana
we all agree that's what that means
that's what you're pointing out
you know and we're we're as as human
beings as
um you know where we're being projected
from somewhere else or there there's a
frequency being hit by our body which is
the receiver
and we're trying to um
you know a align with with what we
truthfully are
words don't always cover all of it
so getting in touch with the with the
feeling side of things
is um is important so um i do want to
jc we're getting up here in time um i
wanted to round anything out anything
else that you wanted to throw in here
definitely do so but
i was thinking um just i would love to
end it on
um i have one question for you and then
i would love to end
on kind of your elevator pitch for
people who are like
they're interested in in your work and
they want to like check out your website
um and um so maybe like your elevator
pitch for that
so like hey if you're ready to you know
he'll heal up like i want to hear
your your trailer what's your what's
your your catching in of new people
because um i think we've caught a lot of
people's attention during the podcast
and i want to send them your way to your
website so i'd like to answer that but
first
can we answer jc what does the world
need more of right now
[Music]
understanding and presence i would say
um yeah just understanding
of other people and um
where the world's at and and compassion
but those are like i think my three
ultimate
understanding presence and compassion
because with those three
we would be untouchable like 100
yeah okay that's a great i love that
answer that's a wonderful answer i've
been asking everybody that lately uh
what does the world need more of right
now
so great response okay now now sell me
on your website send me to your website
what's up with it
send me to my website okay um yeah i
just
it's a space open for
um let me elaborate this a little bit
more a
i wanted to create a space for people to
come in and like
i don't know about you but for me when i
have gone to therapy which i've done for
years and years and years and years i've
really just uh
had it had a hard time i've had a hard
time with like
um opening up and connecting and like i
i've always needed somebody to like draw
things out of me like
an invisible energy rope i need somebody
to like ask me questions and
trigger me and pinpoint things um and so
for me
like i had gone to therapy for you know
probably close to
like three years four years off and on
and i've been too many different
therapists and had to
retell my story and go through like the
whole spiral thing
and i wanted a space to create for
people
where i will trigger you i will draw
things out of you
i will tell you what i see and you know
open that space for you to express
yourself and a space for
you to break down but also give you the
tools and tactics
that you specifically need
individualistically like i give it on
the spot
like a channel on the spot intuitively
like okay you're going through this like
do this
and we'll kind of have a conversation
about what i want the you know next
day to look like or next week to look
like um and yeah so that's kind of what
i do and i
um open up different time frames so i
have like a 30 minute an hour long
reading or have like a two-week process
and month-long process a
three-month-long process
um so it just kind of specifies for how
long people
want to dive in um and what they feel
they need is necessary for their healing
um but yeah so that's that's kind of
what i do and where i'm at and i
i deal a lot with i honestly like a part
of me like wants to
dive into the masculine energy because i
want to feel
i want men and like men mostly men to
feel like they have a space
to open up um i do deal a lot with women
which i love
and like you know opening up that
femininity and
whatnot but i want to you know deal with
both ends of the spectrum
um but i feel like that's kind of really
hard but i just want to throw that out
there i feel like it's really hard for
men to kind of
come to a woman and be like okay i need
help um
but yeah so that's just kind of that's
the space that i create the space that i
open up and
yeah my website i mean i have it on my
instagram but my website
in general is just looking
within.squarespace.com and
that's where you can find when i'm what
i'm up to what's your what's your
instagram handle
um i think it's jc.randle
it's my yeah my name you'll probably
have it on here but
yeah yeah i'll include it in the
description yeah
cool jc i'm so glad that you're doing
this i to me it sounds like um
i uh i don't want to um
the word has its own annotations and um
at different times in society it's used
in different ways and so
um be aware of like what comes up for
you as a listener when i say this word
but
i i think i think what's happening now
in in our collective you know
consciousness and and what we need is
is i think the rebirth of the shaman
character
is actually happening um i i think that
it's it's being reframed it's um you
know
the the person who observes society from
from almost outside of society in a
sense like a
you know the the person who who
goes into the mountains and explores
different realities and different
dimensions and different parts of the
of of the the psychological build up
that we have here
and then they they come back to the to
the world and um
and give gifts of healing and give gifts
of knowledge
and um yeah i i just i think that what
what you're doing and
and what um a lot of people are doing
you know self-help authors and people
who are
um just helping people heal um are kind
of like the
it seems to me like it's just the
rebirth of the of the shaman character
the the reintroduction of a
shamanistic way of thinking into our
modern society and i think it's needed
i think it's beautiful i think it's
wonderful i think it's helpful
and uh i'm super glad that you're doing
it and
just just as a fellow human who's trying
to help people out too
jc thank you for doing what you're doing
thank you
i appreciate that yeah i'm super
grateful and
everything just kind of fell into the
perfect place for it to
correlate into reality so i'm super
grateful for that and 100
shaman that's super funny that you say
that like uh
sorry i'm gonna like sidetrack here for
a second um i
went to this event and like we were
creating stuff out of like
driftwood this is like pre-coded um
creating stuff out of driftwood and i
literally made this like
shaman stick almost like just like i
don't know i saw him i was like oh
that's cool i'm gonna like wrap some
stuff around it and like create this and
it looks like this shaman's stick and
then i
went and saw my grandma right after that
and she's like the
more like she's intuitive like that's
the line where i get it she's like
and she's like oh jc hughes stepped into
her showmanship or whatever she called
it and she's
she's so out there but like so funny and
i was just like
grandma that's insane i literally just
like made a shaman's cake like at this
event i was just as in my car
like but that's so funny that you say
that that's really funny i don't i mean
i'm not gonna
correlate myself like i don't really
understand or
what that means or what that looks like
but yeah but yeah that's when you
brought that word up yeah i think that
word is uh you know where
we're we're again taking a word that was
um used at a specific time
in human history that specifically made
sense for that time in history so
to reintroduce it obviously it's going
to have all of the old annotations it's
going to have some new annotations
um we're a society who absorbs a lot of
content
in in the form of television video
movies
tv series and these sorts of things so
any versions of the word shaman that are
using those are kind of what
fills the the spot in our psyche right
away and so i think just
leaving room to to uh kind of wonder
like what did the shaman character do
for for its society back then for it's
for its people for its community
and um what are what what are modern
shamans doing for their community and
what are modern healers doing for their
communities
there's a lot of correlations and and i
think uh having those
like those um yeah like like finding
things that resonate you know like like
your grandma
saying that like that's i don't know you
know you never know maybe
maybe there is some uh some intuitive
hints there
into what you should be doing and what's
actually going on so
it all comes so full circle yeah 100
but yeah thank you so much i'm super
excited i got to hop on here and
as your podcast has progressed and you
know listening to all the people that
you've
worked with like putting this out there
like that's your own
showmanship your own form of healing
people too so
i can appreciate that respect that so
much so
yeah excellent yeah i appreciate you
coming on twice now that's basically i
mean with with all this stuff
i'm just someone who's like i'm going
through my own [__] i'm not i'm just
definitely far from perfect never have
been
um i'm just trying to stumble and trip
through things
out loud to some extent you know and and
basically like everything that i post
every podcast that i do every time i
finish with something i
put it up with this here i hope this
helps
here i hope this helps here i hope this
helps like that's my mantra you know
like that's
that's what i try to do here so i hope
this has helped you listeners
um i know that i feel like me personally
i feel like just this conversation has
helped me already so thank you jc
thank you for being vulnerable thank you
for sharing your work
um listeners check out her website
follow her on instagram
um if you haven't drink any water today
you're out of your mind what are you
doing bro
you dry bones just crusty dusty
oh you know i'm cringing at you not
drinking water you're not drinking water
i'm trying to kill everybody into
drinking more water
okay that's a good perspective because
i've had one drink of water today
jc you're crusty and dusty man oh man
you need to get some
all right we got to end this podcast
because you need to go drink some water
my friend
you're correct thank you so much all
right have a good day listeners have a
good day jc thanks again
bye yeah have a good one junkyard love
fans where are you at right now are you
present is your mind
in the clouds is your head in the sky
are you grounded
are your feet touching the earth are you
looking for something
next to listen to are you projecting
letting these algorithms and letting the
suggestions
take away your life don't do that just a
reminder to get present
to make the decision next that you want
to make don't just get caught up in
spending a whole day
listening to youtube uh or podcasts even
if it's mine i just want the best for
you
take care of yourself live your life be
present relax
your shoulders relax your face muscles
get your bare feet on the ground outside
just
go and be go and exist and remember
life is more than just online life is
more than just all this technology
get present love yourself peace out
we'll see you next episode